<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Don't work. Be hated. Love someone.]]></title>
  <link href="http://zheren.hu/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://zheren.hu/"/>
  <updated>2012-08-29T21:33:22+08:00</updated>
  <id>http://zheren.hu/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Zheren (Ben) Hu]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[A pocket PC I used to have. Good old days&#8230;]]></title>
    <link href="http://zheren.hu/blog/2011/07/30/8283443447/"/>
    <updated>2011-07-30T00:00:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://zheren.hu/blog/2011/07/30/8283443447</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="http://zheren.hu/tumblr_files/tumblr_lp6hzhqm8S1qhbqolo1_500.png"/><br/>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[How people say "Happy Birthday" on social media?]]></title>
    <link href="http://zheren.hu/blog/2011/07/13/7605551346/"/>
    <updated>2011-07-13T00:00:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://zheren.hu/blog/2011/07/13/7605551346</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The sample size of the data is only 38, which is based on the observation of my own wall.</p>

<p><img height="310" width="500" src="https://lh4.googleusercontent.com/-v0v3JOWu2nY/Th6JbzC2sPI/AAAAAAAAAkQ/hPxZxAsgc4w/s800/chart_1.png"/></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[500 when tried to sign up Google+ keep me posted list]]></title>
    <link href="http://zheren.hu/blog/2011/06/28/7037799911/"/>
    <updated>2011-06-28T00:00:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://zheren.hu/blog/2011/06/28/7037799911</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="http://zheren.hu/tumblr_files/tumblr_lnjhfah1lk1qhbqolo1_500.png"/><br/>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[First impression on @github for Mac]]></title>
    <link href="http://zheren.hu/blog/2011/06/24/6858653448/"/>
    <updated>2011-06-24T00:00:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://zheren.hu/blog/2011/06/24/6858653448</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img height="366" width="400" alt="@github for Mac" src="https://lh5.googleusercontent.com/-ratLlAxp6ZU/TgLhbS29sxI/AAAAAAAAAh0/43gNAigKVIs/s400/github%252520for%252520mac.png"/></p>

<ol><li>The overall UI looks great and I can prolly stop using gitk for all my github projects.</li>

<li>There are some problems during scanning existing repos. Some of my repos do not get scanned correctly. Not sure why.</li>

<li>I hope there will be more keyboard shortcuts support so that I can go back and forth between commit view and repo view easily.</li>

</ol>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[This is prolly my 1st web app ever and it is still on the web!]]></title>
    <link href="http://zheren.hu/blog/2011/06/22/6818658455/"/>
    <updated>2011-06-22T00:00:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://zheren.hu/blog/2011/06/22/6818658455</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.shyahs.com/xstd/xswy/huzeren/myself.htm">Click here!</a>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[From Wordpress to Tumblr]]></title>
    <link href="http://zheren.hu/blog/2011/06/18/6679810433/"/>
    <updated>2011-06-18T00:00:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://zheren.hu/blog/2011/06/18/6679810433</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Thanks to the script below for enabling me transfer my Wordpress posts to my newly created Tumblr almost painless. The script transferred most of stuff including title, tags, and categories correctly. Couple things are worth noting:</p>

<ul><li>All Wordpress posts lost paragram formatting during the transfer so I had to go through each post to fix it. (This was the time I felt glad that I did not have many posts)</li>

<li>Table Contentin posts are gone and I cannot quickly figure out how to create table content in a Tumblr post. Thus I decided to take a screenshot and inserted it as an image.</li>

<li>Tumblr Theme installation process is very confusing, maybe just because I am a newbie. Every time I clicked <strong>install</strong> on a theme, it goes to my blog customize page, but it still displays those sample contents with my blog name; I clicked <strong>save+close</strong> several times, it did not work and I had to specifically click <strong>save</strong> to make it work. Is <strong>save+close</strong> supposed to be a superset of <strong>save</strong>?</li>

<li>The content editor for post is very narrow in Chrome (v12.0) and I cannot resize it. Is it a feature because Tumblr is a microblogging platform?</li>

</ul><p><a href="http://mwunsch.tumblr.com/post/454540000">mwunsch</a>:</p>

<blockquote>

<p>Here’s a little command-line tool for importing WordPress posts to Tumblr. It works okay. Download it, <code>chmod 755</code>, and run it like this:</p>

<pre><code>$: ./wp2tumblr wordpress.xml

</code></pre>

<p>Where <code>wordpress.xml</code> is a WordPress XML export. You can pass an optional <code>--group</code> parameter if you want to publish to a blog other than your main.</p>

<p>Some caveats:</p>

<ul><li>All posts are <em>regular</em> posts.</li>

<li>Some post meta information is lost in the ether.</li>

<li>Comments are lost.</li>

<li>Anything not set to <em>published</em> will be saved as a Tumblr draft.</li>

</ul><p><strong><em>Update</em></strong>: I’ve updated the script to throttle requests to try to stay within the rate limit on <code>api/write</code>.</p>

<p>If there are less than 60 posts to import, this script uses Weary’s <code>batch</code> method for asynchronous requests. Each request is performed in its own thread (or your Ruby VM of choice’s approximation of a Thread). In other words, the script is really fast if you have less than 60 posts, but if not, will take 1 second per post to make sure you don’t exceed the rate limit.</p>

<p><strong><em>Update</em></strong>: The good folks at Tumblr upped the rate limit on api/write from 10 to 60. Thanks Marco!</p>

</blockquote>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Install MySQLdb Python driver on Mac OS]]></title>
    <link href="http://zheren.hu/blog/2010/10/04/6676601163/"/>
    <updated>2010-10-04T00:00:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://zheren.hu/blog/2010/10/04/6676601163</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>If you get this error when you try to build it, please read the <em>README</em> carefully because you need to install <a href="http://pypi.python.org/pypi/setuptools">setuptools</a> first.</p>

<blockquote>

<p><span>ImportError: No module named setuptools</span></p>

</blockquote>

<p>If you get this error when you try to build it, it is because mysql is installed in a customized path on your Mac.  <span></span></p>

<blockquote>

<p><span>EnvironmentError: mysql_config not found</span></p>

</blockquote>

<p>You just need to modify this link in the site.cfg.  <span></span></p>

<blockquote>

<p><span>#mysql_config = /usr/local/bin/mysql_config</span></p>

</blockquote>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tomcat Character Encoding Configuration for UTF-8]]></title>
    <link href="http://zheren.hu/blog/2010/05/14/6676601159/"/>
    <updated>2010-05-14T00:00:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://zheren.hu/blog/2010/05/14/6676601159</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Tomcat is still a very popular servlet container, but the default character encoding for Tomcat is ISO-8859-1. This causes problem if you want your website to be international because you will need to UTF-8 encoding. There is an <a href="http://wiki.apache.org/tomcat/FAQ/CharacterEncoding#Q5">instruction</a> on Tomcat wiki talking about how to set character encoding. I just want to add some extra points.</p>

<ul><li>If you are using Spring framework, you can use the character filter provided by Spring.</li>

</ul><p><span class="Apple-style-span"><span class="Apple-style-span">

<pre> &lt;!--<br/>    - This is useful because current browsers typically do not<br/>    - set a character encoding even if specified in the HTML page or form<br/> --&gt;<br/> &lt;filter&gt;<br/>    &lt;filter-name&gt;encodingFilter&lt;/filter-name&gt;<br/>    &lt;filter-class&gt;org.springframework.web.filter.CharacterEncodingFilter&lt;/filter-class&gt;<br/>    &lt;init-param&gt;<br/>        &lt;param-name&gt;encoding&lt;/param-name&gt;<br/>        &lt;param-value&gt;UTF-8&lt;/param-value&gt;<br/>    &lt;/init-param&gt;<br/>    &lt;init-param&gt;<br/>        &lt;param-name&gt;forceEncoding&lt;/param-name&gt;<br/>        &lt;param-value&gt;true&lt;/param-value&gt;<br/>    &lt;/init-param&gt;<br/> &lt;/filter&gt;<br/><br/> &lt;filter-mapping&gt;<br/>    &lt;filter-name&gt;encodingFilter&lt;/filter-name&gt;<br/>    &lt;url-pattern&gt;/*&lt;/url-pattern&gt;<br/> &lt;/filter-mapping&gt;</pre>

</span></span></p>

<ul></ul><ul><li>Make sure that the character filter is the <strong>FIRST</strong> in your filter chain. This is actually very important since filter chain does have order.</li>

</ul>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[An Annoying IE Bug]]></title>
    <link href="http://zheren.hu/blog/2009/09/22/6676601178/"/>
    <updated>2009-09-22T00:00:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://zheren.hu/blog/2009/09/22/6676601178</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Yesterday, I came across a very annoying IE bug: IE XMLHTTP implementation turns a standard 204 response code into a pretty random 1223 status code. Apparently it is an IE bug for a while, at least for both IE 7 and IE 8. And I found out a pretty cool <a href="http://www.enhanceie.com/ie/bugs.asp">website</a> to track IE bugs.</p>

<p>I am not an <a href="http://www.msboycott.com/super/">anti-Microsoft</a> person, but Microsoft Internet Explorer is really one of a kind. These days when the whole industry is trying to embrace standards, IE products are behind the industry standards movement. IE6 is already a disaster for web developers and a lot of new <a href="http://mashable.com/2009/08/11/orkut-ie6/">websites</a> already stop supporting it. IE8 has made some good improvements, hope Microsoft can incorporate more open standards into its IE product and fix those annoying bugs.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[SNS in China]]></title>
    <link href="http://zheren.hu/blog/2009/07/11/6676601194/"/>
    <updated>2009-07-11T00:00:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://zheren.hu/blog/2009/07/11/6676601194</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Today I read an <a target="_blank" href="http://www.donews.com/Content/200907/6ebcc799-d9b8-46e3-bca3-ba153b4e5b7a.shtm">article</a> from a Chinese tech site, it talks about the development of SNS industry in China. As we all know, after MySpace and Facebook took off in US, there are tons of copycats in China such as XiaoNei.com, KaiXin.com, KaiXin001.com and etc. There are a lot of competition between these early adopters, and you can even tell from their names: KaiXin.com and KaiXin001.com belong to two different companies and one of them is suing the other one. There are a lot of new comers, for example, Sohu.com is launcing its own SNS site. There are a lot of problems within this industry in China. Although they copy the idea pretty fast, even the look and feel, they do not have a good technical architecture and a good business model.</p>

<p>Architecture wise, they have similar platform concept as Facebook and 3rd party developers can develope applications on that. But it does not provide a very good support for 3rd party applications developers and it leads to very few applications on the platform compared to thousands on Facebook.</p>

<p>Business model wise, they position themselves as SNS, but what they are doing are off the track of real Social Network concept. They use webpage games to attract users which is fine. But most webpage games provide things like gambling, stealing and etc. which are not positive. Some of them are trying to shift their business model to Twitter model.</p>

<p>Overall I think there is still a long way for SNS in China. Even in US, Facebook and MySpace are trying to find a good way to grow their business in a healthy way. SNS in China is trying to find a localized business model for China, and hopefully they can find a healthy way.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Exit Strategy NYC]]></title>
    <link href="http://zheren.hu/blog/2009/07/08/6676601120/"/>
    <updated>2009-07-08T00:00:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://zheren.hu/blog/2009/07/08/6676601120</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Yesterday one of my coworkers dropped us an email point out to an interesting iPhone App: <a href="http://www.exitstrategynyc.com/" target="_blank">Exit Strategy NYC</a>. <a href="http://bwong.net" target="_blank">One of the author</a> actually works full time in Morgan Stanley as IT associate. I have to say it is a very nerdy and handy app. Even for myself, everyday I take the same subway and I already figure out where the door opens when the train stops depending on different model of the train. $1.99 for an app like this, I guess quite a few New Yorkers will buy it. Since I do not use MTA that much, I guess I probably gonna skip this one.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Register a cool domain name]]></title>
    <link href="http://zheren.hu/blog/2009/07/07/6676601133/"/>
    <updated>2009-07-07T00:00:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://zheren.hu/blog/2009/07/07/6676601133</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>As we all know, common domains include .com, .net, .org, .info, .biz and etc. But at the same time, there are a lot of <a target="_blank" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Country_code_top-level_domain">ccTLD (country code top-level domain)</a>. Thus by using these ccTLDs, you can register some cool domain name for yourself especially for people with a Chinese name. For example, .HU, Hungary domain, can be used for people whose last name is 胡, spelled as Hu in English; .GU, Guam domain, can be used for people whose last name is 顾. Please check out the table below:</p>

<p><img alt="Cool Domain Name for Chinese" src="https://lh4.googleusercontent.com/-3oEz0_JZKC4/Tf10IYv5A0I/AAAAAAAAAhU/gTdo2gz5Zbs/s800/Screen%252520shot%2525202011-06-18%252520at%2525208.49.08%252520PM.png" width="577" height="450"/></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Accessibility and You]]></title>
    <link href="http://zheren.hu/blog/2009/07/06/6676601157/"/>
    <updated>2009-07-06T00:00:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://zheren.hu/blog/2009/07/06/6676601157</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Today I went into an interesting talk by Chris Heilmann: <a target="_blank" href="http://www.wait-till-i.com/2009/06/05/accessibility-and-you-my-brownbag-presentation-at-ebaygumtreepaypal/">Accessibilty and You</a>. Before I got into this talk, accessibilty means to provide better user interface for people with disability. Apparently I am wrong. In this talk, Chris mentioned: &#8220;The fastest growing segment of the <span>U.S. </span>population is the 65 and over group.&#8221; <a target="_blank" href="http://lifetwo.com/production/node/20071114-the-middle-aged-discover-facebook-a-little-late-to-the-game">Some statistics</a> from facebook has a similar indication of the market shift. Baby boomers in US starts to become potential consumers of Web 2.0 technologies. When you are aging, you may start to have problems with vision, hearing, movement and etc. Thus accessibility is important for this group of people. Apple, a company providing great user experiences, just released a good feature with their newest <a target="_blank" href="http://www.apple.com/iphone/iphone-3gs/voice-control.html">iPhone 3GS</a>. I guess there is no best user interface, only better one =).</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
