<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: English | Don't work. Be hated. Love someone.]]></title>
  <link href="http://zheren.hu/blog/categories/english/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://zheren.hu/"/>
  <updated>2013-01-02T20:51:36+08:00</updated>
  <id>http://zheren.hu/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Zheren (Ben) Hu]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Munin Setup for  Nginx and Mongodb Monitoring on Ubuntu 11.10]]></title>
    <link href="http://zheren.hu/blog/2012/12/06/munin-setup-for-nginx-and-mongodb-monitoring-on-ubuntu-11-dot-10/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-06T22:00:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://zheren.hu/blog/2012/12/06/munin-setup-for-nginx-and-mongodb-monitoring-on-ubuntu-11-dot-10</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I was trying to set up some kind of monitoring system for our soon-to-be-live
backend system. After some quick research, I decided to use give Munin a try
since it has pretty good community support for all kinds of plugins.
Their <a href="munin-monitoring.org/">homepage</a> plus couple google searches help me
to present the following walkthrough.</p>

<h3>Installation</h3>

<p>Installation is pretty easy on Ubuntu server, for the munin master:</p>

<p><code>
apt-get install munin
</code></p>

<p>for the munin node:</p>

<p><code>
apt-get install munin-node munin-plugins-extra
</code></p>

<h3>Configuration</h3>

<h4>munin master</h4>

<p>First you need configure <code>/etc/munin/munin.conf</code>, in general you just need to
specify the host tree, bascially all munin nodes you want to monitor. Something
like this:</p>

<p>```
[server1.domain.com]</p>

<pre><code>address [your_server_ip_address]
</code></pre>

<p>```</p>

<p>One caveat here is to make sure the server name <code>server1.domain.com</code> you specify
here matches the configuration later you do on your node. If these two do not
match, it will not get data at all.</p>

<p>Then you need to make sure your munin monitoring webpage can be accessed. If you
are using nginx like me, just create a file under
<code>/etc/nginx/sites-available/munin</code> with config like this:</p>

<p>```
server {
  listen 80;
  server_name monitor.domain.com;
  location / {</p>

<pre><code># Host Based auth
#allow 11.12.22.55/32;
#deny all;
# Passwd auth
auth_basic            "Restricted";
auth_basic_user_file  munin_auth_pass;
root /var/www/munin;
</code></pre>

<p>  }
 }
```</p>

<p>I am using basic password authentication and for that you need
to create a password file. For the above configuration, you need to have a file
<code>/etc/ngnix/munin_auth_pass</code>:</p>

<p><code>
username:encrypted_password
</code></p>

<p>If you use ruby, the easiest thing to get the encrypted_password would be:</p>

<p><code>
&amp; irb
1.9.3 :001&gt; "password".crpyt('salt')
=&gt; "sa3tHJ3/KuYvI"
</code></p>

<p>Now you are all set to have a munin monitoring page running and password
proteced at <code>monitor.domain.com</code>.</p>

<h4>munin node</h4>

<p>Munin node, by default, is using port 4949, you can configure it and just make sure the
port is not blocked by the firewall, which happened to me in the
beginning. Configure <code>/etc/munin/munin-node.conf</code> and two key configurations are:</p>

<p>```
host_name server1.domain.com</p>

<p>allow ^127.0.0.1$
allow [regex_of_ip_address_of_munin_master]
```</p>

<p>You need to make sure the host name you set here matches the one you put in your
munin master conf. Now if you do a <code>sudo service munin-node restart</code>, you should
be able to see graphs on your munin master for several existing monitor items
like system, networking and etc.</p>

<p>If you want to monitor more items like nginx and mongodb, you can find most
third party plugins in <a href="https://github.com/munin-monitoring/contrib/tree/master/plugins/">munin github project</a>. Let's say you want to monitor nginx, what you need to do is:</p>

<p><code>
cd /usr/share/munin/plugins
sudo wget -O nginx_combined https://raw.github.com/munin-monitoring/contrib/master/plugins/nginx/nginx-combined
sudo chmod +x nginx_combined
sudo ln -s /usr/share/munin/plugins/nginx_combined /etc/munin/plugins/nginx_combined_[munin node ip address]
sudo service munin-node restart
</code></p>

<p>And you need to configure <code>/etc/munin/plugin-conf.d/munin-node</code> to add these two
lines:</p>

<p><code>
[nginx*]
env.url http://localhost/nginx_status
</code></p>

<p>You can add more plugins with similar approach and different plugins may have
their own custom config to make sure it gets data correctly.</p>

<p>This whole process took me more than a whole afternoon to figure out, hopefully
this blog can help you move faster with munin.</p>

<p>Happy monitoring!</p>

<h3>References</h3>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://play.datalude.com/blog/2012/01/munin-nginx-mysql-ubuntu/">http://play.datalude.com/blog/2012/01/munin-nginx-mysql-ubuntu/</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.cowboycoded.com/2011/01/12/password-protect-your-entire-site-with-nginx/">http://www.cowboycoded.com/2011/01/12/password-protect-your-entire-site-with-nginx/</a></li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[CocoaPods Tip #1: How To Use Edge Version of A Library?]]></title>
    <link href="http://zheren.hu/blog/2012/09/14/cocoapods-tip-number-1-how-to-use-edge-version-of-a-library/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-14T10:55:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://zheren.hu/blog/2012/09/14/cocoapods-tip-number-1-how-to-use-edge-version-of-a-library</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I am using <a href="http://cocoapods.org/">CocoaPods</a> to manage my iOS project. Because a lot of iOS libraries are open source, sometimes you have to use the edge version of the library to get the latest pathes to make things work. If you read through articles on the <a href="https://github.com/CocoaPods/CocoaPods/wiki/Dependency-declaration-options">project wiki</a>, and it seems to be pretty easy and just like how developers do in Gemfile:</p>

<pre><code>pod 'LibName', :git =&gt; 'https://url/of/the/github/repo'
</code></pre>

<p>If you try to enter <code>pod install</code>, it probably won't work the way you expect: you will still use the old library. So the easiest way to solve this problem is to <strong>delete your Pods director</strong> and do <code>pod install</code>. And this is still the way to make it work for CocoaPods 0.14.0.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[How much time did it take us to register the company in China?]]></title>
    <link href="http://zheren.hu/blog/2012/02/07/how-much-time-did-it-take-us-to-register-the-company-in-china/"/>
    <updated>2012-02-07T00:00:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://zheren.hu/blog/2012/02/07/how-much-time-did-it-take-us-to-register-the-company-in-china</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>2 months!!!</strong></p>


<br/>


<p>For more info, please check <a title="公司注册的那点事儿" href="http://9kmiles.wordpress.com/2011/11/26/%e5%85%ac%e5%8f%b8%e6%b3%a8%e5%86%8c%e7%9a%84%e9%82%a3%e7%82%b9%e4%ba%8b%e5%84%bf/">here</a> (sorri, it is in Chinese =P)</p>


<br/>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[My experiences with Chinese Major Banks (for Expats and Returnees)]]></title>
    <link href="http://zheren.hu/blog/2011/12/15/my-experiences-with-chinese-major-banks-for-expats-and-returnees/"/>
    <updated>2011-12-15T00:00:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://zheren.hu/blog/2011/12/15/my-experiences-with-chinese-major-banks-for-expats-and-returnees</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I have been in China for about 4 months and half now and I am "honored" to have the opportunity to deal with several major local banks in China. As you may know, China banking system are mainly controlled by four major national-owned banks: ICBC, CCB, ABC and BOC. I dealt with three of them in 4 months: ICBC, ABC and CCB.<br/></p>

<br/>


<p>Let me start with ICBC. It is the largest of four, so when I wanted to open an account in Hangzhou, I decided to go to ICBC first for the brand. Unfortunately because of the <a title="工行开户趣闻" href="http://9kmiles.wordpress.com/2011/08/14/%e5%b7%a5%e8%a1%8c%e5%bc%80%e6%88%b7%e8%b6%a3%e9%97%bb/">stupidity of their banking system</a>, they had my name wrong in their system for the account I had in college. Because of that, I would not be able to open any new account with ICBC throughout the country unless I went back to that original branch and change my name in the system with my ID. (Notes: China banks are very fragmented, e.g. ICBC Shanghai is kinda independent from ICBC ZheJiang Province, which means I cannot do that name change thing in Hangzhou). And after that I had to go to ICBC twice because our server provider uses them as their bank. I did the exact same transaction in two different branches in Shanghai and they follow totally different workflow. And in order to do a simple transaction, I had to talk to 2 different staff. The process is horrible.<br/></p>

<br/>


<p>For ABC, after I got turned down by ICBC and I ended opening the account in ABC. The staff is pretty friendly and I opened my online banking as well in order to use my account for online payment with Alipay. In China, online banking is still not that popular, so you have to pay some money to open it. And because of pirated software, the internet security is pretty bad as well. Thus when you open online banking account, they will give you a USB drive with security token in it and you have to use it every time you access online banking and doing online payment. So for the security USB drive from ABC, the good part is it works pretty well with VirtualBox under Mac OS X. (Yeah, those USB drives only work under Windows, so if you have a Mac like me, congratulations! You either need to do bootcamp or go with VirtualBox). Fortunately as I said, ABC one works with VirtualBox. After I opened the account with ABC, I started to experience the bad part, their online banking system sucks! I have experiences several failures when I tried to do online payment. And it was not even in their peak time during Taobao sale. It was really annoying. I am sure ABC spends a lot of money on their system, but I have to say it does not work very well at all!<br/></p>

<br/>


<p>CCB, the second among the four banks, with which I have both business account and personal account with them. For the personal account, everything seems to be cool, but I have problem with their security USB token. It does not work with VirtualBox at all. I did some Google search and it turns out it only works with VMWare Phusion. I guess this is called "You get what you pay for". Since I don't wanna buy or install a pirated VMWare software, I have to use my old school ThinkPad T60 to do transactions now. For the business account, different branches have different levels. I went to one branch to do some deposit, I told the teller to put the correct reason for the money, but in the end she still put the wrong reason for it. Luckily that did not cause any problem for the money to go through, otherwise I would have had to do it twice.<br/></p>

<br/>


<p>For my readers, key takeaways from my own experiences(highly biased) are:<br/></p>

<ul><br/>
    <li>If you use VirtualBox on Mac, try not to use CCB. And ABC one works pretty well!</li><br/>
    <li>ICBC services suck! Maybe because they are No. 1 and they do not need to improve anymore. You cannot become No. 0 like it is in computer system, right?</li><br/>
    <li>ABC services are good for me, but the bankend system prolly is the worst.</li><br/>
    <li>All these banks are very inefficient and it takes you in average 30 minutes to do a simple business there. And overall their technology is behind their US peers.</li><br/>
</ul>


<br/>


<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Failure of Retargeting]]></title>
    <link href="http://zheren.hu/blog/2011/11/19/failure-of-retargeting/"/>
    <updated>2011-11-19T00:00:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://zheren.hu/blog/2011/11/19/failure-of-retargeting</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Retargeting is a very common technique in online advertising business these days, but it is a very simple technology. Sometimes it "magically" brings high lift for advertising, but because of its simplicity, it can cause some epic fail.<br/></p>

<br/>


<p>I have been using NewRelic services these days, so I go to its site pretty often. Today when I was reading an article on 9to5mac.com, I found out that there are 8 ads about NewRelic on the same page for me. It is not 1, not 2, not 4, IT IS EIGHT ads about the same company. And these 8 ads almost have the same creative. Seriously?! Really?!<br/></p>

<br/>


<p>I am not able to take a full screen shot of this page, but this page is a great example of epic failure of retargeting.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
