<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: China | Don't work. Be hated. Love someone.]]></title>
  <link href="http://zheren.hu/blog/categories/china/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://zheren.hu/"/>
  <updated>2012-11-24T20:44:52+08:00</updated>
  <id>http://zheren.hu/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Zheren (Ben) Hu]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[How much time did it take us to register the company in China?]]></title>
    <link href="http://zheren.hu/blog/2012/02/07/how-much-time-did-it-take-us-to-register-the-company-in-china/"/>
    <updated>2012-02-07T00:00:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://zheren.hu/blog/2012/02/07/how-much-time-did-it-take-us-to-register-the-company-in-china</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>2 months!!!</strong></p>


<br/>


<p>For more info, please check <a title="公司注册的那点事儿" href="http://9kmiles.wordpress.com/2011/11/26/%e5%85%ac%e5%8f%b8%e6%b3%a8%e5%86%8c%e7%9a%84%e9%82%a3%e7%82%b9%e4%ba%8b%e5%84%bf/">here</a> (sorri, it is in Chinese =P)</p>


<br/>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[拿什么拯救我们的文化产业？]]></title>
    <link href="http://zheren.hu/blog/2011/10/19/how-to-save-chinas-entertainment-business/"/>
    <updated>2011-10-19T00:00:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://zheren.hu/blog/2011/10/19/how-to-save-chinas-entertainment-business</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>蛮早就想写这个帖子了，那天和Matt聊天，他，作为一个在中国没有生活多久的人，和我聊到了关于中国如今的文化产业。他的出发点是中国的动漫产业，他是一个动漫爱好者，所以来到中国后也入乡随俗地想看一下中国的动漫，可惜都令他很失望，失望之余，他不禁感叹如今的中国似乎已经没有什么能够向世界输出的文化产业方面的东西了。当我们还在说着中国上下5千年的悠悠历史的时候，我们很多时候说的还是过去老祖宗的东西，的确孔孟的思想影响了世界，特别是对我们的邻居日本和韩国的影响非常深，但这都是过去的事情了。<br/></p>

<br/>


<p>看看现在，从我那个时候开始到现在的年轻人基本都是看日本漫画长大的；音乐，从热衷港台明星、到哈日、现在的哈韩，特别是韩国，一个只有区区5千万人口的国家，他们的流行音乐可以毫不夸张地说是红遍全世界了；电视剧，虽然国内如今年产n万部的电视剧，但是又有多少是精品呢？看来看去还是好多的港台剧、日韩剧、以及美剧；电影，就更不用说了，我是到了美国才感觉到好莱坞的强大，每个星期五还真的就是有这么多电影上演，中国看来看去就这么几个导演，新的导演拍个好片子还会被禁。<br/></p>

<br/>


<p>中国5千年对外输出文化，在很长一段时间内也建立了中国大国的形象，这个形象不仅仅只是在经济上的，同样韩国最近几年对外的文化输出，不仅给韩国带来了可观的外汇收入，也越来越提升了韩国在世界各地的形象。中国如今GDP是世界第二了，但是在形象方面和很多软条件方面还是有很大差距，这个不是在美国时代广场上租个大屏幕就可以搞定的，需要更多在文化上潜移默化的改变别人的想法。<br/></p>

<br/>


<p>其实在中国所有的文化产业中，有一个行业最近对外输出很大：游戏产业。这个在前几天的<a href="http://weibo.com/1750070171/xt7gflp0t">某游戏公司</a>融到巨资就可以体现出来，我身边有很多做游戏的朋友，第一桶金大部分都是在国外赚到的，不论是在Facebook平台上，还是独立的网页游戏。一个游戏行业的朋友也预言，网络游戏业会成为中国互联网行业第一个在外国做成功的行业。这些固然是好事，只是美中不足的是，大部分成功的游戏为了迎合国外的市场，都做成了西方的主题，从商业角度没有任何问题，只是我作为一个旁观者，希望如果有越来越多用中国主题做的游戏能够在国外受到欢迎就好了，这不仅会是中国互联网行业的一个骄傲，也会是中国近代文化产业成功对外输出的一个范例。</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[喜欢上海的理由]]></title>
    <link href="http://zheren.hu/blog/2011/09/08/reasons-that-i-love-shanghai/"/>
    <updated>2011-09-08T00:00:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://zheren.hu/blog/2011/09/08/reasons-that-i-love-shanghai</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>记得高中的时候，立波啤酒在上海有一个几乎人人皆知的广告《立波啤酒——喜欢上海的理由》，特别是那首<a href="http://v.youku.com/v_show/id_XNTA2Mjk5NDQ=.html">广告歌</a>是深入人心啊，这个星期让我加一个喜欢上海的理由：<strong>上海有关部门批准网站备案效率最快</strong>！<br/></p>

<pre>上海是我长大成人的所在，带着我所有的情怀；<br/>
第一次干杯，头一次恋爱，在永远的纯真年代；<br/>
追过港台同胞，迷上过老外；<br/>
自己当明星，感觉也不坏；<br/>
成功的滋味，自己最明白；<br/>
旧的不去，新的不来，<br/>
城市的高度，它越变越快，<br/>
有人出去，有人回来，<br/>
身边的朋友，越穿越新派，<br/>
上海让我越看越爱，<br/>
好日子，好时代，<br/>
我在上海，立波也在。</pre>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[工行开户趣闻]]></title>
    <link href="http://zheren.hu/blog/2011/08/14/my-funny-story-about-opening-account-in-icbc/"/>
    <updated>2011-08-14T00:00:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://zheren.hu/blog/2011/08/14/my-funny-story-about-opening-account-in-icbc</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>回国后天天都能遇到有趣的事情：今天去工行开户，因为住的对面就有一个，也比较相信工行是大银行，开开心心去开户了。结果到了那里，搞笑的事情发生了：<br/></p>

<br/>


<p>第一，根据工行规定，每个身份证号只能有一个网银登陆，因为我原来很久以前用的学校的工行卡开通过网银了（我自己都不记得，多少年前的事情了），所以我要注销原来那个，要过一天才可以开通新的。<br/></p>

<br/>


<p>第二，更搞笑的在后面，银行的人一查我名字，我好好的一名字，后面尽然加了10个@符号，我是搞技术的，一看就知道肯定是哪个搞数据库或者系统的对于短的名字自定义加了一些字符凑齐比特数，这下银行的人也傻眼了，说没法开户，因为我身份证名字和系统名字差了10个@，我必须要到我开户行去更新我的“真名”。<br/></p>

<br/>


<p>哎，这么大一个上市的国有银行，当年，甚至现在还有可能是全世界市值最高的银行，技术竟然是如此，我承认银行的技术本来就比较保守落后，可是做成这样地步的，实在是让我很担心啊。在微博上发了一贴，结果我朋友幽默了一把，说估计工行和微博有合作关系，特别喜欢@符号，只能是怒其不争啊。</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hosting Service in China]]></title>
    <link href="http://zheren.hu/blog/2011/08/13/hosting-service-in-china/"/>
    <updated>2011-08-13T00:00:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://zheren.hu/blog/2011/08/13/hosting-service-in-china</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>When you start working on an Internet startup, one of few things you will think about first is how I should host my service. In US, where Internet infrastructure is ahead of the rest of the world, this becomes less a problem for startup because there are so many choices like AWS, GAE or even Microsoft Azure. However, situation in China is very different: first, both AWS and GAE do not have servers in mainland China, which means it is really slow to access either of them; second, legally it is not a good idea to use foreign servers anyway, because in order for you to run Internet business in China, you have to register your website with government and that requires you have serves physically located in China.<br/></p>

<br/>


<p>In the old time, some Chinese startups will start with a foreign VPS (usually in US) such as Linode for the development and initial launch while they wait for the approval of government organizations. After that, the startup has to buy its own servers and pay data centers to put their servers on the rack which is a pretty big investment upfront for a small startup.<br/></p>

<br/>


<p>With the development of Chinese Internet infrastructure and the boom of tech startups, these days there are more and more local companies start to offer VPS or cloud hosting services. Companies I am aware of are:<br/></p>

<ul><br/>
    <li>http://aliyun.com: this is a service provided by <a href="http://alibaba.com">Alibaba</a>, one of the 3 biggest Internet companies in China. Their service looks like a VPS service with a pretty clear <a href="http://phpwind.aliyun.com/show/ecc">fee structure</a>. It starts with 199 RMB a month (about 30 USD) for a server. It provides a beta version cloud database service which does backup and a lot of maintenance work for you. It supports only MySQL for now.</li><br/>
    <li>http://netbank.cn: this is a HangZhou company which provides VPS service as well. It provide three basic plans and on top of that you can customize according to your need. For a Intel XEON520 single core, 2GB memory and 30GB harddrive server with 100MB bandwidth from China Telecom (this is not the amount, just the speed)  , it costs you around 3000RMB/year.</li><br/>
    <li>http://xingcloud.com: this is a startup from Kai-Fu Lee's <a href="http://chuangxin.com">Innovation Works</a>, currently it markets itself as a cloud platform for game developers. With the reputation of Kai-Fu Lee and the strong team behind it, XingCloud could be an interesting player to watch in this area.</li><br/>
</ul>


<br/>


<p><span class="Apple-style-span" style="color:#444444;font-family:Georgia, 'Bitstream Charter', serif;font-size:16px;line-height:24px;">A very interesting thing to note about hosting service in China is: you need to pay for bandwidth of different ISPs, because if you don't do that, your service will be slow for users using that ISP. There are six major ISPs here, and two of them are the biggest: China Telecom and China Net Communication (CNC). For a startup, you probably should pay bandwidth for these 2 ISPs. Because of this bandwidth thing, the cost of Chinese Internet Video companies are much higher than Youtube.</span><br/></p>

<br/>


<p><span class="Apple-style-span" style="color:#444444;font-family:Georgia, 'Bitstream Charter', serif;font-size:16px;line-height:24px;">What did we do?</span><br/></p>

<br/>


<p><span class="Apple-style-span" style="color:#444444;font-family:Georgia, 'Bitstream Charter', serif;font-size:16px;line-height:24px;">Before we got here, we started with a <a href="http://www.linode.com">Linode</a> monthly account. We have been using that for the past week, it is just super slow because of GFW and the physical distance. Sometimes our terminal window just halts there. So we have decided to switch to a local provider since we can try out their service 3 months for free. That will make huge difference because the average ping value for Linode server is about 350ms while the local one is about 5ms. By the way, there is a <a href="http://ping.chinaz.com/">service</a> in China to test your ping value from different parts of the country with different ISPs. </span><br/></p>

<br/>


<p>Hope this information can give you an idea how hosting works in China. =)</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
